EMEKA BENNY OBINWA

Lagos, Nigeria

| E: emeka@benny.com.ng, obinwaemekabenny@gmail.com | In: www.linkedin.com/in/benny-emeka

INTRODUCTION

Technical Support Specialist and Cloud Engineer with over six years of experience and expertise in providing enterprise-level technical support and infrastructure workload administration. Can offer well developed skills at conceptualizing and implementing technological solutions across multiple OS platforms. Demonstrated history of effectively handling up to L3 support cases for both onsite and remote teams while focusing on improving business processes and delivering the best end-user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microsoft 365 Administration: SharePoint, Teams, Exchange Online, Power Automate
- Google Workspace Administration
- Operating Systems: Everything Windows, Linux, MacOS, iOS and Android
- Windows Server Administration: MS Active Directory, Group Policy Management, Windows PowerShell
- Virtualization: VM-Ware, Hyper-V
- Protocols: CP/IP, LDAP, LAN/WAN, VoIP, WLAN, DNS, DHCP, RDP
- Computer Hardware, Software, Firmware and Network Installation, Configuration and Support
- Remote and Onsite Technical Troubleshooting
- Databases: MySQL
- Firewalls and Endpoint Security: Sophos XG, Sophos Intercept X
- Programming Language/Scripting: Python, Bash, Javascript
- Project Management Jira
- CRM Zendesk
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, GCP, IBM Cloud
- Version Control Systems: Git, GitHub
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions
- IAC: Terraform
- Container/Orchestration: Docker, Docker swarm, Kubernetes
- Languages: English (Fluent), German (Basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bureau for Rights-Based Development (BRD) – Remote

Technical Support

Jun. 2021 - Date

Key Duties and Contributions:

- Office 365 Administration (SharePoint Online).
- Microsoft Azure AD Support and Administration.
- Website Management.

International Energy Services Limited (Engr. Design Centre) – Lagos, Nigeria

IT Administrator
IT Support Engineer
Key Duties and Contributions:

Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2021 Jun. 2015 - Oct. 2017

Supported over 300 employees spread across 3 major locations (Nigeria, Ghana and Paris), with crossfunctional teams of engineers, lab scientists, business developers, expatriates and managers.

- Managed all in-house company servers, firewall and distributed network, ensuring security and data integrity through access controls, backups, and firewalls, maintaining a 99.9% uptime per annum.
- Administered Microsoft 365 workloads (Exchange Online, SharePoint Online, Teams), as well as all inhouse computer infrastructure and ensured over 85% compliance with IT and organizational standards.
- Repeatedly set up and managed Microsoft 365 workloads that allowed for cross-organizational communication, collaboration and resource sharing, leading to the successful completion of several engineering projects worth over 100 million dollars in revenue.
- Reduced printer consumables and paper usage by 30% by designing and deploying a digitalized QR code incident report form for the organization's Health and Safety department.
- Co-authored usage manuals and co-administered end-user training on in-house enterprise applications achieving a 60% reduction in problem escalation and resolution.
- Improved business process efficiency and productivity by 45% across the entire organization by digitalizing tedious manual and repetitive in-house departmental processes using Microsoft 365 apps like Planner, To Do, Forms, SharePoint and Power Automate.

Cyberspace Networks Limited – Lagos, Nigeria

Technical Support Engineer Technical Support Intern Key Duties:

Aug. 2013 - Oct. 2013 Mar. 2012 - Aug. 2012

- Installed and configured WiMAX radios, SensaPhone devices and Fiber Optic network connections for new sites or clients and ensured installation standards were adhered to 100% of the time.
- Carried out site surveys for prospective clients requiring our services and submitted site reports after each visit.
- Frequently troubleshot, optimized, and resolved faulty radio network connections, both on-site and remotely for over 150 clients at the time.
- Worked frequently in the Customer Service department on nights, weekends, and public holidays, responding to and resolving and closing all customer tickets within my shift, making sure to escalate when necessary.

EDUCATION

B. Eng. Information and Communication Engineering, Covenant University, Ota, Ogun State. (2013).

CERTIFICATIONS

- Google IT Support Professional (February 2021)
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (July 2021)
- Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate (August 2021)

WORK ACHIEVEMENT AND AWARDS

- Was promoted from IT Support Engineer to IT Administrator six months into my second stint at International Energy Services Limited September 2019.
- Letter of commendation for outstanding performance in the delivery of IT Support in ensuring ongoing projects were undisrupted during the pandemic– 2020
- Google Africa Developer Scholarship (GADS) 2021 participant– Google Cloud Track
- Nokia & BIT Scholarship 2021 Challenge Finalist AWS Cloud DevOps Track